# Oshinder singh

E-mail: oshinder44@gmail.com Phone: 9720930558

Address: village malakpur, PO+DISTT. - HAPUR, UP, 245101

# **Professional Summary**

Highly dedicated and performance driven professional with 4 years of total experience comprising 2 years as a Cloud Engineer, 8 months as a Digital Marketing Executive and rest as a Business Analyst with technical knowledge on AWS, **EC2**, IAM, S3, VPC.Actively looking for a Cloud Solution Architect position with a fast-paced and ambitious company that can offer development training, project-based learning and mentoring program.

### Professsional skills

- AWS
- VPC
- S3
- EC2
- LOAD BALANCER
- IAM
- PYTHON
- GIT
- Docker
- · Encoder & Decoder

## Work experience

#### **ABPNEWS NETWORK**

MARCH 2019 — PRESENT

Junior Engineer

TECHNOLOGY USED: AWS, VPC, IRD, Stream expert Modulator, Git

#### **JOB RESPONSIBILITY:**

- Worked on Amazon Web Services (EC2, ELB, VPC, S3, CloudFront, IAM, RDS, Route 53, CloudWatch, SNS,)
- Hands on Experience in AWS Elemental Server(T2 Large).
- Setup/Managing Linux Servers on Amazon (EC2, EBS, ELB, SSL, Security Groups, RDS and IAM).
- Creating/Managing AMI/Snapshots/Volumes, Upgrade/downgrade AWS resources (CPU, Memory, EBS)
- Installed and Setup Web Servers ( Apache and Tomcat ), DB Server ( MySQL)
- Hands on experience in working with various Version Control Systems, mosyly GIT.
- Maintaining the user accounts (IAM) in AWS cloud.

#### Dishtv

sep 2018 — feb 2019

**Downlink Specialist** 

TECHNOLOGY USED: IRD, COMMON TERMINAL POINT, Remote desktop, Stream expert, Modulator, Dish Tuning,

JOB RESPONSIBILITY

Oshinder singh

- •L band Signal Distribution
- •Installation and configuration of professional decoders, Harmonic, CISCO, Ericson .
- •Knowledge of decoder and encoder

#### **IMARC**

NOV 2017 — JUNE 2018

Digital Marketing Executive

JOB RESPONSIBILITY:

Worked on SMO, LINK BUILDING, OFF PAGE, ON PAGE, And also used webmaster tools, made website on wordpress. I also worked on tools such as keyword planner and created links as well as articles on Twitter, Facebook, Google Plus, Linkedin.

Trifid Research

June 2016 — March 2017

**Business Analyst** 

To gather the required information from the client side and provide all the necessary details to clients relating to the stock market.

## Education

B.tech (Information Technology)

JULY 2012 — JULY 2016

Quantum Institute of technology

## personal skills

- · Consistent learning attitude
- Problem solving
- · Effective team working

Oshinder singh 2